Ted Hughes papers, 1940-1999
Emory University
- Writings by Ted Hughes, circa 1949-1990, Series 2; Boxes 57-86; OP2-58a; 105-107; OBV1
  - Collected poems, 1957-1995, Subseries 2.2; Boxes 59-80; OP2-28, 105-107
    - "Your Mother's Bones Wanted to Speak, They Could Not," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Remains of Elmet, "The Long Tunnel Ceiling" and Subseries 2.3 "The German at his yacht"] (Box 63, Folder 59)
    - Cave Birds, TS (early version) [Contains several poems that did not appear in collection, including he unpublished "He Shouted"] (Box 63, Folder 60)
    - Cave Birds, TS (Incomplete; missing "The Summoner" and "After there was nothing there was a woman"] (Box 63, Folder 61)
    - Cave Birds, Typescript narrative synopsis (Box 63, Folder 62)
    - Cave Birds (Faber edition), Corrected proof (Box 63, Folder 63)
    - Cave Birds, Rewrite instructions, MS, undated (Box 63, Folder 64)
    - Gaudete (1977)
    - Gaudete, Manuscript draft, 1st half (incomplete) (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Gaudete, Manuscript draft, 1st half (incomplete) (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Gaudete, Manuscript draft, Unpublished drafts of 1st half (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Gaudete, Early plan with explanations of editing symbols (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Gaudete, Manuscript draft of timetable for Lumb's whereabouts in Gaudete (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Gaudete, Manuscript notes on themes (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Gaudete, Manuscript and typescript summary of plot for shortened reading with corrections (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Gaudete, Miscellaneous MS and TS pages (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Prologue, MS (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Prologue, TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Gaudete, "Lumb's Dream is Sprung;" Subseries 2.2: Remains of Elbert, "The Canal's Drowning Black" and "Rhododendrons;" and Subseries 2.6, What is the Truth?, "Badger"] (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - "Again," MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - "The Alsatian," MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - "A Mile Away," MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - "Argument," MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - "Behind the Bar," MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - "Betty," TS (Box 64, Folder 16)
    - "Binoculars," MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 17)
    - "The Bridge Inn Bar," MS and TS [variant title: "The Bar Room at the Bridge Inn"] (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - "But Still the Enraged," MS and TS [variant title: "The Enraged"] (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - "The Cathedral," MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - "Dr. Westlake" [#1], MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 21)
    - "Dr. Westlake" [#2], MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 22)
    - "Easy and Strong," MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 23)
    - "Estridge" [#1], MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 24)
    - "Estridge" [#2], MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 25)
    - "Estridge and Evans," MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 26)
    - "Estridge's Younger Daughter Jennifer," TS (Box 64, Folder 27)
    - "Evans," MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 28)
    - "Felicity" [#1], MS and TS [variant title: "Margaret"] (Box 64, Folder 29)
    - "Felicity" [#2], MS and TS [variant title: "Margaret"] (Box 64, Folder 30)
    - "Felicity" [#3], TS [variant title: "Margaret"] (Box 64, Folder 31)
    - "Felicity" [#4], MS and TS [variant title: "Margaret"] (Box 64, Folder 32)
    - "Garten" [#1], MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 33)
    - "Garten" [#2], TS (Box 64, Folder 34)
    - "Garten" [#3], MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 35)
    - "Garten" [#4], MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 36)
    - "Garten" [#5], MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 37)
    - "Garten" [#6], MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 38)
    - "Garten" [#7], MS and TS (Box 64, Folder 39)
    - "Hagen is Striding," MS and TS [variant title: "Within Minutes" and "Hagen Within Minutes"] (Box 64, Folder 40)
    - "Holroyd," MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - "In Estridge's Lens," MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - "In His Hardening Lenses," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Three Book, "The Mayfly is Frail"] (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - "In the Bar at Bridge Inn," MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - "Lumb" [#1], MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - "Lumb" [#2], MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - "Lumb" [#3], MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - "Lumb" [#4], MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - "Lumb" [#5], MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - "Lumb" [#6], MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - "Lumb's Dream is Sprung," MS and TS [variation on the Prologue] (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - "Lumb's Eyes," MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - "Maud" [#1], MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - "Maud" [#2], MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 14)
    - "Maud" [#3], MS and TS [variant title: "What is Maud Doing?"] (Box 65, Folder 15)
    - "Maud" [#4], MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 16)
    - "Maud" [#5], MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 17)
    - "Maud" [#6], MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 18)
    - "Maud" [#7], MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 19)
    - "Mrs. Davies," MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 20)
    - "Mrs. Garten," TS (Box 65, Folder 21)
    - "Mrs. Holroyd," MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 22)
    - "Mrs. Westlake," MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 23)
    - "The One Glance," MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 24)
    - "Pauline Hagen," MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 25)
    - "The Scherzo," MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 26)
    - "Westlake's Grey Daimler," MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 27)
    - "Women," MS and TS (Box 65, Folder 28)
    - Epilogue, MS (Box 65, Folder 29)
    - Gaudete Poems
    - "At the top of my soul," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "Take What You Want But Pay For It"; Subseries 2.3: "A Solstice"; and Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box 65, Folder 30)
    - "A bang-a burning," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Calves harshly parted from their mamas," TS [See Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "Walt, MS" and Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Churches Topple," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The coffin, spurred by its screws," TS [See Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "Take What You Want But Pay For It" and "Us He Devours, MS" and Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Collision with the earth has finally come," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS and Subseries 2.6, What is the Truth?, "Fly" and "Treecreeper"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The dead man lies, marching here and there," TS [See Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "Take What You Want But Pay For It" and "Walt, MS"; Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS; and Subseries 2.6: Under the North Star, "Wolf"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "A doctor extracted," TS [See Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "Take What You Want But Pay For It"; Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS; and Subseries 2.6: What is the Truth?, "Fox"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Every day the world gets simply," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS and Subseries 2.6: Under the North Star, "Grizzly Bear" and "Wolverine"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Glare out of just crumpled grass," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Grass blade is not without," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Remains of Elmet, Early plan and Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box 65, Folder 31)
    - "Having first given away pleasure," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Hearing your moan, echo, I chill. I shiver," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "Take What You Want But Pay For It" and Moortown, "If mouth could open its cliff"; and Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box 65, Folder 32)
    - "The huntsmen, on top of their swaying, horse-towers," TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box 65, Folder 33)
    - "I hear your congregation at their rapture," TS (Box 65, Folder 34)
    - "I heard the screech, sudden," MS and TS [variant title: "A Near Miss"] (Box 65, Folder 35)
    - "I know well" [See Subseries 2.3: "Hungry for Sunlit Wall" and Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "I said goodbye to earth," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "I see the oak's bride in the oak's grasp" [See Subseries 2.3 "Disarmament," MS and TS] [variant titles: "Natural History," "Tyrants Skulls," and "Skulls"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "I skin the skin," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: New Selected Poems, 1957-1994, "Remembering Teheran" and Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box 65, Folder 36)
    - "I watched a wise beetle," TS [See Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "Take What You Want But Pay For It" and Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "In a world where all is temporary," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The lark sizzles in my ear," TS (Box 65, Folder 37)
    - "Looking for her form" [See also Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "Take What You Want But Pay For It"; Subseries 2.3: "Hungry for Sunlit Wall"; and Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Music, that eats people," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Moortown, "The earth locked out the light" and "If mouth could open its cliff"] (Box 65, Folder 38)
    - "Once I said lightly," TS [See Subseries 1.5: Undated correspondence-Alphabetical, Hunter, David] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "A primrose petal's edge," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The sea grieves," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "She rides the earth," TS [See Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "Take What You Want But Pay For It"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Sometimes it comes, a gloomy flap of lightning," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The sun, like a cold kiss in the street," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The swallow - rebuilding," TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS and Subseries 2.6: What is the Truth?, "Fox"] (Box 65, Folder 39)
    - "This is the maneater's skull," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Trying to be a leaf," TS (Box 65, Folder 40)
    - "The viper fell from the sun," TS [See Subseries 1.5: Undated correspondence-Alphabetical, Hunter, David] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Waving goodbye, from your banked hospital bed," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS and Subseries 2.6: What is the Truth?, "Fox"] (Box 65, Folder 41)
    - "What steel was it the river poured," TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box 65, Folder 42)
    - "What will you make of half a man," TS [See Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "Take What You Want But Pay For It"; Subseries 2.3: "A Solstice"; and Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "When the still-soft eyelid sank again," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Who are you?" MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box 65, Folder 43)
    - "Your tree - Your oak," MS and TS [variant titles: "Black Oak," "Oak," "Totem," and "Guardian"] [See also Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "Walt, MS;" Subseries 2.3: Crow poems, "Crow at Large" and "The Infinity of Womb Failures;" Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS; and Subseries 2.6: Under the North Star, "Brooktrout," "Eagle Owl," "An Evening Seal," "Puma," and "The Snow-Shoe Hare"] (Box 65, Folder 44)
    - Gaudete, Outline notes (Box 65, Folder 45)
    - Gaudete, Typescript of 1st half w/ corrections (Box 65, Folder 46)
    - Gaudete, Typescript (carbon) of 1st half with corrections (Box 65, Folder 47)
    - Gaudete, Typescript (photocopy) of 1st half with corrections (Box 65, Folder 48)
    - Gaudete, Typescript of 2nd half (incomplete) Gaudete (Box 65, Folder 49)
    - Typescript (carbon) of 2nd half (incomplete) (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Gaudete, Typescript (manuscript, carbon and photocopies) of 2nd half (incomplete) [Different order than final version] (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Gaudete, Typescript (photocopy) of Epilogue and 2nd half with introduction to Epilogue [See also Gaudete "Lumb" [#1], MS and TS] (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Gaudete, Typescript and carbon typescript of 2nd half with corrections (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Gaudete, Typescript (carbon and mock-ups) (incomplete) (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Gaudete, Complete typescript with corrections (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Gaudete, Complete typescript (carbon) with corrections (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Gaudete, Incomplete typescript (carbon) with corrections (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Gaudete, Complete typescript (photocopies) [different from published version] (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Gaudete, Complete typescript with corrections and notes for publisher (pp. 1-99) (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Gaudete, Complete typescript with corrections and notes for publisher (pp. 100-209) (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Gaudete (Harper and Row), Uncorrected proof (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Gaudete (Faber), Uncorrected proof (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Gaudete (Faber), Corrected proof (copy 1) (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Gaudete (Faber), Corrected proof (copy 2) (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Gaudete (Faber), Corrected proof (copy 3) (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Gaudete, (Faber) Corrected proof w/ book jacket (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Gaudete (Faber), List of corrections (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Gaudete, Movie/play plan (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - Gaudete, Manuscript drafts of movie/play (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Gaudete, Typescript of movie/play (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Gaudete, Typescript (2 carbons) of movie/play (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Orts (1978)
    - "Air," MS and TS (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - "Are they children or are they senile?," TS (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - "At some juncture the adult dies," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "Take What You Want But Pay For It"] (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - "At the bottom of the Arctic sea, they say," TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - "Before I was born, you were a spirit," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Better, happier, to stay clear of the pure," TS [See Subseries 2.6: What is the Truth?, "Fox"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The buzzard mews-," TS (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - "By the splitting, spilling, fly-crazing," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The cat, craning over the long grass," MS (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - "The cat, craning over the long grass," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The Cathedral, for all its defenses," TS (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - "Churches darken like scabs," TS (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - "The cry is coming closer," TS (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - "The cut stone," TS (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - "Does it matter how long," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Each new moment my eyes," TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - "The earth is strong, faithful, true, and," TS (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - "The engine under the car-bonnet," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "The express, with a bang," TS (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - "Eye went out to hunt you," TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - "The fallen oak sleeps under the bog," TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS and Subseries 2.6: What is the Truth?, "Fox"] (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - "For weights of blood," TS [See Subseries 2.2: New Selected Poems, 1957-1994, "Remembering Teheran" and Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Hathershelf," TS (Box 68, Folder 19)
    - "He did all that he thought he wanted to do," TS (Box 68, Folder 20)
    - "He sickened," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Capricho, "A deathly sleep swallowed me;" Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "Take what you want but pay for it;" and Subseries 2.3: "Between her footsoles and her crown"] (Box 68, Folder 21)
    - "He sits grinning, he blurts laughter," TS (Box 68, Folder 22)
    - "Huge global trouble all to earn," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Wolfwatching, "Take What You Want But Pay For It"] (Box 68, Folder 23)
    - "If searching can't find you," TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box 68, Folder 24)
    - "In the zoo," TS [See Subseries 1.5: Undated correspondence-Alphabetical, Hunter, David and Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Like the future oak invisible," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Look Back," TS (Box 68, Folder 25)
    - "Lucrecia," TS (Box 68, Folder 26)
    - "The mother of the tree," TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box 68, Folder 27)
    - "Ophelia," TS (Box 68, Folder 28)
    - "Ophiuchos," TS (Box 68, Folder 29)
    - "The Queen of Egypt," TS (Box 68, Folder 30)
    - "Searching, I am confronted again," TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box 68, Folder 31)
    - "Sitting under the downpour," TS (Box 68, Folder 32)
    - "Skin," MS and TS (Box 68, Folder 33)
    - "So much going on," TS (Box 68, Folder 34)
    - "Stilled at his drink," TS (Box 68, Folder 35)
    - "Sunday bells," TS (Box 68, Folder 36)
    - "They brought you a lit-up flying city," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box 68, Folder 37)
    - "The volcano," TS (Box 68, Folder 38)
    - "Where you wait" TS [See also Subseries 2.3: "Between her footsoles and her crown"; Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS; and Subseries 2.6: The Pig Organ, "Fox"] (Box 68, Folder 39)
    - "The white shark," TS (Box 68, Folder 40)
    - "A wild drop flies in space," TS (Box 68, Folder 41)
    - "Words bring wet lumps of earth," TS (Box 68, Folder 42)
    - "You have come down from the clouds," MS and TS (Box 68, Folder 43)
    - "You have made me careless," TS [See Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Your eyes are poor," TS [See Subseries 2.5, The Pig Organ, MS and Subseries 2.6: What is the Truth?, "Fox"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "Your touch jerks me," TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS and Subseries 2.6: What is the Truth?, "Weasel"] (Box 68, Folder 44)
    - Orts, List of titles (Box 68, Folder 45)
    - Orts, Page proofs with corrections (Box OP8a)
    - Orts, Typescript with numbered poems (incomplete) [some different selections than those published] (Box 68, Folder 46)
    - Orts, Typescript with numbered poems in green ink [mostly from Orts, some from other works] (Box 68, Folder 47)
    - "Caprichos" (Unpublished Collection, ca. 1978)
    - MS notebook containing "Athene's Owl," "Face was necessary," "He wanted to be here," "I walk," "Man stepping from every tedious thing," "Nevertheless Rejoice," "The oracle," "The prisoners," "Reckless Head," "The road which was so long," "To take aim and to thicken power," "What legs prop up," "When dawn lifts the eyelid," "When it comes down to it," all from the "Caprichos" collection. (Box 68, Folder 48)
    - "Athenes Owl," TS [unpublished] (Box 68, Folder 49)
    - "Dead, she became space-earth," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Moortown, "Dead, she became space-earth"] (Box 68, Folder 50)
    - "A Deathly Sleep Swallowed Me," MS and TS (Box 68, Folder 51)
    - "The earth locked out the light," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Moortown, "The earth locked out the light"] (Box 68, Folder 52)
    - "Face was necessary," TS [variant title: "If you doubt this face"] [See also Subseries 2.2: Moortown, "Face was necessary"] (Box 68, Folder 53)
    - "For Leonard and Lisa," TS [variant title: "He casts off"] [See also Subseries 2.2: A Primer of Birds, "For Leonard and Lisa"] (Box 68, Folder 54)
    - "He wanted to be here," MS and TS [unpublished] [variant title: "His arrival"] [See also Subseries 2.2: Moortown, "The earth locked out the light" and "If mouth could open its cliff"] (Box 68, Folder 55)
    - "He was frightened," MS and TS [unpublished] (Box 68, Folder 56)
    - "I walk," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Moortown, "I walk"] (Box 68, Folder 57)
    - "If mouth could open its cliff," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Moortown, "If mouth could open its cliff," and River, "Creation of Fishes"] (Box 68, Folder 58)
    - "A Man stepping from every tedious thing," TS (Box 68, Folder 59)
    - "Nevertheless rejoice, MS and TS [unpublished] (Box 68, Folder 60)
    - "No came from the earth," MS and TS [unpublished] (Box 68, Folder 61)
    - "The oracle,"TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Moortown, "The Oracle"] (Box 68, Folder 62)
    - "The prisoners," MS [unpublished] (Box 68, Folder 63)
    - "Reckless Head," MS [variant titles: "When you shouted into a dark building" and "When you shouted into a dark house"] [See also Subseries 2.2: New Selected Poems, 1957-1994, "Reckless Head"] (Box 68, Folder 64)
    - "The road which was so long," MS and TS [unpublished] (Box 68, Folder 65)
    - "Snow" [See Subseries 2.3: "All Heroes Are the Same" and "A Grained Common Pebble"] (Box -, Folder -)
    - "To take aim and to thicken power," TS [unpublished] [variant title: "When I take aim"] (Box 68, Folder 66)
    - "What legs prop up," TS [unpublished] (Box 68, Folder 67)
    - "When dawn lifts the eyelids," MS and TS [unpublished] [variant title: "Before his eyes dawned"] (Box 68, Folder 68)
    - "When it comes down to it," TS (Box 68, Folder 69)
    - "With biting of neck," TS (Box 68, Folder 70)
    - Moortown Elegies (1978)
    - "Birth of Rainbow," MS (Box 68, Folder 71)
    - "Bringing in New Couples," MS (Box 68, Folder 72)
    - "Coming Down Through Somerset," MS and TS (Box 68, Folder 73)
    - "Couples under Cover," MS and TS (Box 68, Folder 74)
    - "The Day He Died," MS (Box 68, Folder 75)
    - "Dehorning," MS (Box 68, Folder 76)
    - "February 17th," MS and TS (Box 68, Folder 77)
    - "Feeding Out-wintering Cattle at Twilight," MS and TS (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - "The Formal Auctioneer," MS (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - "Foxhunt," MS and TS (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - "Hands," MS and TS (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - "Happy-calf," MS (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - "Last Load," MS (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - "Last Night," MS (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - "Little Red Twin," MS and TS [variant title: "Little Twin] (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - "March Morning Unlike Others," MS (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - "New Year Exhilaration," MS (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - "Now You Have to Push," MS [variant title: Now He Has to Push"] (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - "Orf," MS and TS (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - "Rain," MS (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - "Ravens," MS and TS (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - "She Has Come to Pass," TS (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - "Sheep, Parts I and II," MS and TS (Box 69, Folder 16)
    - "Snow Smoking as the Fields Boil," MS (Box 69, Folder 17)
    - "Struggle," MS (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - "Surprise," TS (Box 69, Folder 19)
    - "Teaching a Dumb Calf," MS (Box 69, Folder 20)
    - "Tractor," MS (Box 69, Folder 21)
    - "Turning Out," MS and TS (Box 69, Folder 22)
    - "While She Chews Sideways," MS (Box 69, Folder 23)
    - Moortown Elegies, Typescript with printers mark (Box 69, Folder 24)
    - Moortown Elegies, Typescript (photocopy) (Box 69, Folder 25)
    - Moortown Elegies, Early galley proof with corrections (Box OP9)
    - Moortown Elegies, Proof (Box 69, Folder 26)
    - Broadside poems from Moortown Elegies (Rainbow Press, 1979), Proofs [includes Memory ["Your bony white boned back"] which was not included in final version] (Box OP10)
    - Moortown (1979)
    - Artwork (Harper & Row) (Box 69, Folder 26a)
    - "Actaeon," TS [See also Subseries 2.2: Cave Birds, TS (early version)] (Box 69, Folder 27)
    - "Buzz in the Window," MS and TS [See also Subseries 2.5: The Pig Organ, MS] (Box 69, Folder 28)
    - "Children," MS and TS (Box 69, Folder 29)
    - "Dead, she became space-earth," MS and TS (Box 69, Folder 30)
    - "Down," TS and corrected table of contents which suggests "Down" was at one point intended for inclusion in Moortown (Box 69, Folder 31)
    - "The earth locked out the light," MS and TS (Box 69, Folder 32)
    - "Earth-Numb," MS and TS (Box 69, Folder 33)
    - "Everything is Waiting," MS (Box 69, Folder 34)
    - "The Express, with a Bang," TS [See Subseries 2.2: Moortown, "A God" and Primer of Birds, "For Leonard and Lisa"] (Box -, Folder -)